TIM WILLIAMS

Customer Experience Expert

PERSONAL DETAILS

Timathome99@hotmail.com 07947 926292

www.linkedin.com/in/timwilliamssilurum

SKILLS

Customer Experience

CRM

Customer insight

Client management

Networking

Behavioural science

Presenting

Content creation

Neuromarketing

Stakeholder interviews/workshops

ATTRIBUTES

Curious

Pragmatic

Collaborative

Questioning

Resilient

PERSONAL SUMMARY

A deeply experienced planner and customer experience specialist driven by a fascination for behavioural science and customer insight.

Extensive knowledge of all aspects of customer acquisition, growth, and retention derived from having worked both agency and client-side.

Familiar with an extensive suite of planning methodologies from journey mapping and segmentation to stakeholder workshops and inductive research.

Constantly seeking out and applying the latest relevant thinking from adjacent fields.

Skilled at working collaboratively with senior level clients.

A published and broadcast authority on customer experience.

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Planning Director, FourForty: The Customer Expectation Agency, Nov 2020 - current A niche CX agency built around the proposition that trust is the ultimate driver of customer behaviour and loyalty.

Actively involved in proposition development, new business and IP creation with several podcasts and published articles on numerous aspects of customer experience. Currently, I'm in the process of writing a book on customer trust.

Planning Director, Oliver Wyman/Draw, 2014 - Nov 2020

Leading the planning function within a digital agency. Responsible for CRM/CX strategy, content marketing/thought leadership and senior support for new business. Taking a lead in the fields of CRM/CX, engagement and loyalty strategies, proof of concept testing, proposition development, eCRM comms strategy, new business pitches, and content marketing.

Projects included Future.Now, Historic Royal Palaces, ASICS, FlyBe, ACCA and McArthurGlen and a market positioning study for a leading text analytics client.

Planning Director, Underwired, 2010-14

Headed the planning team within this eCRM agency with clients across sportswear, hospitality, and charity sectors.

Key activities included:

- Auditing of client customer data, insights, and current strategies
- Recommendations on data enhancement and analytical opportunities
- Qual and quant primary research requirements
- Mapping customer lifecycle and 'moments of truth' by channel

MOTIVATORS

A 'two pipe problem'

Uncovering the unexpected

Autonomy

- Development of '3D' segmentations and journey design
- Designing consumer 'golden question' and feedback mechanisms
- CRM requirements definition
- Development of an audience strategy review for a major charity
- Teaching on Planning at the IDM and other events

Head of Customer Insight, Three UK, 2009 - 2010

Following extensive previous retention experience within the telco sector, I was brought in to set up a customer insight function to provide the Board with the means to make more informed and timely operational decisions.

Key deliverables included:

- Developed and delivered regular customer dashboard report and analysis for senior leadership team
- Identified, consolidated, and interpreted the relationships between numerous customer perception and behaviour measures with internal performance KPIs
- Working with Customer Service, Marketing and Billing teams to inform more effective customer management at key life cycle 'moments of truth'
- Providing leadership team with key insights on how to develop positive network perception amongst customers
- Proposition and business case development

2008-9: Contract roles in FS sector (Norwich Union and AXA UK)

- Produced business requirements for operational 'voice of customer' analysis and subsequent dashboard reports
- Delivered strategic and 'real time' customer feedback pilots across multiple business units to support retention, satisfaction, and business requirements for 'Treating Customers Fairly' compliance

2007: CRM Manager, B&Q

Defined the overarching Customer Management Strategy using balance of 'push' CRM and 'pull' Customer Experience Management (CEM) elements.

Pre 2007: Extensive telco and airline sector experience

I acted as Head of CRM Strategy at Orange with a focus on churn reduction; defined the business requirements for a digital self-serve project at O2 and developed proactive retention campaigns at T-Mobile.

I worked in Marketing and commercial roles at Air New Zealand and United Airlines.

QUALIFICATIONS

BA (Hons), History, University of York

Postgraduate Diploma in Business and Administration